Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
Original Rip By mstoll
Resync/Corrections By Chuck
- Good morning. ma'am.
- Morning.
You must be Mrs. Macahan.
I am.
22 years old. a little over 6 feet.
light brown hair. You'd be Luke Macahan.
Drop the gun belt. boy.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm sorry to inform you. ma'am.
but your son's under arrest...
...for desertion
from the United States Army.
Name's Grey.
You move that scatter gun.
I'll empty that saddle.
And if I don't?
- I'll drop you right there.
- Zeb!
You were really gonna kill that man.
Kate. his life is gonna be
in danger wherever he is...
...as long as Grey's after him.
Luke will fight him. and
Grey will kill him.
So we're back to that.
Kill or be killed?
If killing would save the life
of one of your children. you'd kill.
You're wrong. Zeb.
Killing your boy was a fair fight.
Killing me ain't gonna bring him back.
That's right. It ain't.
But it's sure gonna pleasure me to
gut-shoot you and watch you die real slow.
Charlie!
The Shoshone and the Arapaho...
...are going against each other
right here on your ground.
You're wasting your breath. Mr. Anderson.
We're staying put.
They got my boy. Zeb.
And I'm gonna keep killing
Arikara till I get him back.
Then we best get to it.
You'll be riding with me?
The sooner we get to your boy...
...maybe I can get the Army off your scent.
When I find the boy. I mean to go right
in amongst them. Zeb.
Boy free.
White Eagle free.
Madigan stay.
You know what you gotta do. old coot.
Cut me loose. boy. and I'll show you
how to throw that thing!
That wouldn't scare a jackrabbit!
That's better.
Cully!
What are you doing here?
I knew you would go home.
That is the way I came.
Now you gotta go back.
I'm staying with you.
Your father. your people...
It is you I want.
Don't you understand?
I'm on the run.
Do not tell me to go away.
I'm tired of men telling me what to do.
I'm not leaving.
Speak now.
Good.
My son has told me
what you have done for us.
Cully wouldn't have done
any less. Little Tree.
No. he would not.
You two were ears of maize
from the same root.
And we thank you.
The only thanks I need
is for you to get well.
That's what Cully would have wanted.
He traded his life for yours.
I will get well.
Good.
You know. you have much to live for.
Everything that was
in the father is in the son.
I know.
Where do you go now?
I go and tell the Army
that Man-Who-Walks-With-Thunder...
...no longer kills Arikara.
Goodbye. Little Tree.
Goodbye.
Mr. Macahan?
Goodbye. friend.
Goodbye. Jeremiah.
What is it? What's wrong?
Someone's coming.
You back-shooter!
Erika.
Luke?
I... I love you.
I should have made you go back.
We were together.
Luke.
The Lord is my strength and my shield.
Worship the Lord
in the beauty of holiness.
Weeping may endure for a night...
...but joy comes in the morning.
Madigan's dead.
Are you sure?
I killed him.
I'm sorry. Zeb.
I know he was your friend.
He was a damn sight more than that.
He was a man with a wife scalped
and a boy took.
He went out to get his boy back
just like anybody else would've done.
He took scalps. Zeb...
...and damn near triggered
an Indian war in the doing.
You or I would've done the same thing.
wouldn't we?
Or maybe you'd rather sit behind that desk
and choke on your rules.
Well. I'm sorry you feel that way.
But no matter. The Army is still grateful.
To hell with the Army.
Macahan.
If it's any consolation...
...what you did may have saved
a lot of lives. Indian and white.
Major. you're a good man...
...but you're blind like the rest of them.
We've already taken most
of the Indian's good hunting grounds.
And we're gonna keep on
till we get the rest of them.
We've slaughtered his buffalo...
...plowed up the ground
he's roamed for generations.
We're killing him off
with smallpox and syphilis.
And if that isn't enough.
we've got half the U.S. Army...
...out there to run him to earth.
Indian's finished. He knows it.
And he's not gonna give up easy.
You'll see more blood spilled
around this country...
...in the next 20 years
than you can measure.
Cully's death didn't save any lives. major.
It just changed a few
of the faces that are gonna die.
Grey?
You and me got some unfinished business.
I lack the authority to arrest you now.
What's the matter? Did you get fired
for losing too many pigeons?
I never missed a man yet. Macahan.
And I'd nail your nephew
but for the government.
Congress just passed Mr. Lincoln's law.
Amnesty for all deserters.
Amnesty?
I figured they'd forget about it
after he was assassinated.
But they didn't.
You know. I've known a lot
of bounty hunters in my time.
I've never seen any of them
hotter on the scent than you.
It must be eating you alive...
...you can't scrag any more of those boys.
Let me tell you something. Macahan.
A deserter shot me in the back at Antietam.
I was facing a Rebel charge
with a company of green kids...
...when I went down. They panicked.
They ran.
Some of them ran all the way home.
Rebels took my position.
broke my line...
...and... And broke...
Maybe you'd like to arrest me.
Aiding a fugitive was
the charge. wasn't it?
- I can't arrest you now.
- Why not?
Your nephew wasn't a legal fugitive
at the time.
The amnesty bill was passed
before I come after him.
I just found out about it.
How many other boys you scrag
before you found out?
None.
But your nephew isn't
out of it yet. Macahan.
There's still a charge hanging over him.
shooting a Missouri sheriff.
I resigned my commission last week.
A lot of the men on my list are wanted
for things other than desertion.
And your boy is right at the top.
Grey.
Let me tell you something.
You come after Luke. ever...
...I'll kill you.
Or I'll kill you.
That's fair enough.
You ask around. I'm not hard to find.
You gonna take on the Arapaho
and the Shoshone?
No. ma'am.
After you left. two men came through
looking for you.
It wasn't social.
I've been out here long enough
to know that look.
Gunmen.
You got a good eye. ma'am.
I ran into them.
What happened?
They're in the ground.
There was a dry spell down in Texas.
Water got scarce.
and then it got valuable.
There's a rancher by the name of Burnett.
He wanted to keep
all the water to himself.
He pushed the farmers out.
The farmers come to me
with everything they owned...
...which on reflection was not very much...
...and they hired me
to protect their interests.
Burnett's men liked to shoot guns.
Those two out there were part of all that.
Why did you come back here?
I come to get you and the kids out of here
before the shooting starts.
I'm sorry.
I can't do that.
Mrs. Macahan.
you're an awful stubborn woman.
Mountain-Is-Long was to be your man.
This is my man.
Is he a better man?
Chief. you don't understand.
Let him speak.
Chief. if I were you. I'd take my braves...
...including the prospective
bridegroom here. and just move out.
Like the lady says. I'm her man.
Shoshone way.
man must prove he's better.
Fights.
The one who lives takes woman.
One who lives?
Man to man...
...till death.
You don't understand. chief.
I don't want your man.
Mrs. Macahan. what you want
has nothing to do with this here.
Chief. I want your word.
If I fight and win...
...you will take your braves and move out
and leave us alone.
We will leave.
But if you lose...
I don't want you to do this.
I don't see as we have any choice.
Wait! Wait!
Let him live!
I'll take Mountain-Is-Long as my man.
Mountain-Is-Long is your man.
Tonight you take him to your bed.
Mountain-Is-Long fine man.
Pretty lady lucky.
We come back in morning.
Oh. I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
No. that's... It's all right.
I sure wish I could've whipped that Indian.
Would it have done any good?
That's one thing
the Shoshones do have is honor.
Claw would've kept his word.
I come here to save your ma's life
and she ends up saving mine.
You really care for her. don't you?
I mean. you coming back the way you did.
That's the first time in memory...
...that I ever done something
that wasn't for myself...
...or money.
What are we gonna do?
Nothing.
You've still got your gun.
Son. that Indian fought me man to man
and he won.
That was the deal.
Now we live with it.
I'm not gonna do it.
I'm not gonna stay in here while that...
Son. you better put that gun down.
One of the first lessons
you learn out here. son...
...is you don't touch another man's iron
without his say-so.
Josh. he's right.
If it's any solace to you. boy...
...I've been aching
to go after that gun myself.
Josh.
You're supposed to be in the barn.
Ma. I can't leave you
in the house alone with that man.
It'll be all right. Josh.
Now go on.
Please. Josh.
If you need me...
I know.
Shoshone are my enemies.
They raid our villages
and kill many warriors.
Chief Claw take women
and children to be slaves.
That has nothing to do with us.
Tonight...
...Mountain-Is-Long was to be your husband.
In the morning. Shoshone return
to celebrate your marriage.
When they come. we will be waiting.
There's an injured man in the barn.
The long knife.
Yes. He needs attention.
I have to change his bandages.
I have no weapon.
I want to change your bandage.
Go ahead. All right.
We should've got out of this...
...while we still had the chance.
This place is gonna be a battleground
come the morning.
You're all gonna be stuck
right in the middle of it.
You were a fool to come back here.
That's not the first time
I've heard that.
You know. after the fighting starts. the...
There might be a...
A chance then for...
For you and your family to skip out.
You go.
You've done everything you could already.
I wasn't talking about myself.
It's funny.
Just a couple of days ago...
...I would never have anything
to do with something like this.
I would've just turned my back
and rode on out.
Why didn't you?
You know why.
Mrs. Macahan. I ain't the only one
that's running.
I'm not going anywhere. Mr. Anderson.
Awful young to be starting so early.
He ain't bad looking either.
Something on his mind
he don't want to talk about.
He's carrying some money.
Morning.
Just leave me alone.
When you get down
to the end of that bottle...
...you're gonna need something else
besides more whiskey.
What is it?
I don't want to talk.
- It might help.
- Will you just get away?
You just looked like you might need
someone to talk to. that's all.
Sorry I bothered you.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
I just don't feel like talking.
I been there.
But believe me...
...it's when you want to be alone
you shouldn't be.
Maybe you should talk.
But if you don't feel like it.
that's all right too.
Can I sit?
It's Claw.
We'll all be killed.
Isn't there anything we can do?
Girls.
- Josh!
- Go back! Go back!
He's only a boy!
For what he has done
your son should die.
Only savages kill children!
The whites are savages.
The white soldiers killed women
and children at Black River.
Eight Arapaho children were
saved because of a white man...
...my brother-in-law Zeb Macahan.
He was almost killed
trying to help your people.
Macahan?
We're Macahans.
This is the house of the White Eagle?
I am the woman of his brother.
Macahan is the man...
...who gave us back the lives
of our children.
Oh. Josh.
We will not return again.
All right. now just hang on to me.
Floor's moving.
I'm not surprised.
Easy. Easy.
- Oh. that's funny.
- What?
The floor... The bed's going up the wall
and slipping down again.
This your room?
It's mine.
Yeah. it's a nice room.
And you're a nice boy.
You ought to be ashamed of yourself
for getting in this condition.
Oh. Well. I got a reason.
I wish I could stay drunk forever.
You've had all of that you can take.
No.
What you need now is some sleep
and lots of it.
You're not gonna like tomorrow.
You're nice.
I'm nice.
You live here long?
While.
The sooner I get out. the better.
Running.
Everybody's running somewhere.
It ain't worth it.
It don't matter.
Lot of men come through here.
Luke. with a lot of problems.
Not many of them as young as you.
There's got to be a girl
mixed up in this somewhere.
The most beautiful girl in the world.
Erika.
Erika?
You loved her?
Loved her.
Killed her.
You killed her?
It was my fault.
I shouldn't have let her stay.
They was shooting at me.
I don't understand.
Who was shooting?
Luke. are you on the run?
I doesn't matter. Nothing matters.
Luke. listen to me.
If you're running.
you shouldn't be getting drunk...
...in a place like this.
Somebody might recognize you.
It don't matter.
They're gonna catch me sooner or later.
Zeb says he won't quit
till somebody kills him.
Who's Zeb?
I don't want to kill anybody.
Never again.
You're wanted for killing somebody?
Morning.
Why?
The reward.
$250.
In this town you know
how many men I'd have to go through...
...for that kind of money?
You just bought my way out of this place.
All right.
I don't have to tell you...
...that I'd give anything I own
to be able to stay.
The girls will want to say goodbye.
I don't think I could handle that.
You do it for me. huh?
When are you leaving?
When my son comes back home.
Oregon?
Mm-hm.
Maybe I'll see you there.
What did it cost?
$20.
You haven't got the reward yet.
My credit's good in this town right now.
I'm gonna hit Denver with a bang.
And the men are gonna take notice.
Some people will do anything for money.
I had him first.
You're a loser. dearie.
Whiskey.
Looks like he's been living in a cave.
eating raw meat.
My kind of man.
You couldn't handle it. honey.
Try that again.
Hot?
Yah. it could even be
too hot for consorting.
Doubt if the heat's ever
stopped you before.
Passing through?
Yeah. same as you.
Fact is. I'm leaving for Denver.
Yeah. I reckon you'll
make out there all right.
Say. uh. maybe you could
help me with something.
I'm looking for a young fella might have
passed through here last day or two?
Why?
Well. uh. he's my nephew.
- His ma asked me to come fetch him back.
- What's his name?
Luke. Luke Macahan.
Sorry. I can't help you.
He's about 23.
six foot or better.
I've seen no one like that.
We've seen no one like that. have we. Tom?
Nope.
Well...
...thanks anyway.
Mister. that young fella
you were asking about?
She lied to you.
He was here.
What she'd lie lie for?
She turned him in for money.
He's locked up in the
town jail right now...
...waiting transfer to Missouri.
Much obliged.
Beats me what some folks'll do
to get out of a day's work.
Uncle Zeb!
- Well. Luke.
- What're you doing here?
Well. something better than you.
looks like.
Well. how'd you find me?
I stopped by the Simonite place.
They said you was gone
so I figured you might be headed home.
Yeah. I was.
But I forgot your advice again.
What happened?
Ah. I got liquored up in the saloon.
told somebody I was wanted.
How long you been in here?
Four days.
That means that sheriff
must've sent that telegram...
...to Missouri for the reward.
Where's he at?
Ah. eating.
Takes up most of his time.
Gotta figure a way
to get you out of here. boy.
You got an idea?
Yeah.
Who are you?! Get them dirty feet
off of my desk!
You watch your mouth. mister.
And keep your hand away from that
gun too. or I'll rip your guts out.
I didn't come all the way
from Missouri...
...to take no lip off
of no small-time law dog!
Missouri? What do you want?
What do I want?
Maybe if you can read that
you can see what it says!
"Deputy"? Deputy?
You don't look like no deputy to me!
And you don't look like no sheriff to me.
Now. my name's Bowie John Christie...
...and I'm the meanest deputy sheriff
Stillman's got!
I come here to pick up that
prisoner you sent the wire about.
- Luke... Luke Macahan?
- That's the one.
How'd you get here so fast? I... I just
sent that telegraph three days ago.
Sheriff Stillman wants that prisoner bad.
That's why he sent me.
Now suppose you make out
some papers...
...and quit giving me so much lip.
I'll be on my way.
Yes. sir.
I... I understand there's a $250 reward
for Macahan.
No. there ain't!
Gone to 500.
If I had my way. you wouldn't be
getting a red cent.
But I supposed they'll figure
you got it coming.
All right. all right.
where do I sign?
Sign right here. deputy. Right here.
Reckon when I'll get my money?
Soon as I get my prisoner
back to Missouri.
Now. suppose you get him out here?
Yes. sir. deputy.
All right. let's go. Macahan.
He's all yours. deputy.
If you think you'll get me
all the way to Missouri...
Shut up and get your hands out.
Handcuffs ain't gonna
do you no good.
Now you listen to me.
you young skunk...
...one more word out of you.
one false move...
...I'm gonna cut your tongue out
and feed it to you for breakfast.
Where's his horse?
Over at the livery stable.
And here's his gear.
All right. you. let's get going.
Thanks a lot. sheriff.
nice doing business with you.
My God.
What?!
Well. how was I to know
he was Macahan's uncle?
- He was wearing a badge.
- But no papers.
Well. he... How'd you know Macahan
was here. anyhow?
I got friends in a lot of towns.
mister. You wired for the reward.
I was afraid something
like this might happen.
How long ago did they leave?
About an hour.
If I were you. I'd form a posse
right away.
I can't form no posse!
Sheriff. after what they did to you...
...you're going to be the laughingstock
of the whole territory...
...unless you run them down.
I'll form a posse.
Give them a rest.
I don't think we got much to
worry about from them.
Looks to me like they'd have
a hard time...
...getting together a poker
game in that town.
Where was you headed? Home?
Yeah. maybe.
I don't know! Someplace.
Sounds to me like
you don't much care.
I don't.
What's eating you?
Aw. nothing I want to talk about.
Make you feel any better
if I told you...
...they passed Lincoln's bill
granting amnesty to all deserters?
Amnesty?
Well. that means Grey won't
be on my tail no more.
Well. I'm afraid there's no
such luck there. Luke.
He's taken to bounty hunting.
He's the kind of man needs to be
tracking somebody down...
...like some men need wars.
Let's get out of here.
Hold it.
Looks like I spoke too soon.
Uncle Zeb. you got yourself in this
too deep already.
You just ride on.
Don't you worry about me.
I don't know
what's eating you. boy...
...but you don't talk like that again.
you hear?
I hear.
Home's too far
to try and outrun them.
Besides. I don't want to lead them
right to the door.
We'll take the long way around.
Lose them.
Hyah!
You all together. boy?
Yeah.
Aw. he's hurt.
Now what're are we gonna do?
Ride double in this country.
they'll both wind up lame.
Let's hole up in those rocks.
give them a chance to rest up.
Uncle Zeb. this is loco
what you're doing.
You just ride on!
It's like I told you. boy...
...we're going home.
we're going home together.
There. in the rocks.
That'll slow them down a while.
What if it doesn't?
Then we're gonna have
some company.
- Best get the horses up in them trees.
- Yo.
The men just don't want this
to go no further.
They took an oath.
It's their duty.
He's just been fooling
with us up to now!
What if he decides
to start drawing blood?
Still their duty.
You're not the law no more!
You're just a bounty man!
And they're wondering why
they should be risking their lives...
...and then split the money with you!
It's your jail Macahan busted out of.
That makes it your responsibility.
doesn't it?
I still have a lot of influence
with the law.
You take your men out of here.
Aames...
...I'll see you crucified.
Well. I'll talk to them.
No. You tell them.
I'll tell them.
Looks like they're starting
to bed down.
Don't think we got nothing
to worry about 'till the morning.
Your horse ought to be ready
to ride by then.
Look. don't you figure it's about
time you was telling me what's...
...what's eating you?
Erika.
Erika? You mean that little gal
that was nursing you?
You'll see her again.
She's dead.
Dead?
Well. I'm sorry. Luke.
I didn't know.
They... They never said nothing.
Yeah. well all I know is I don't give
a damn about anything without her.
You will again.
It will take time.
Don't you understand?
It was my fault!
She left the Bruderhof
to come after me!
If I'd have sent her back.
she'd be alive right now.
But I loved her and I let her stay...
...and she caught a bullet
that was meant for me.
Who done it?
What does it matter now
who done it?
I loved her and now she's gone...
...and I'm never ever gonna
love anyone like that again!
Luke. you will. Time's the only thing
that'll cure something like this.
How do you know?
How the hell would you know
how it feels? Huh?
I...
I'm sorry. Uncle Zeb.
I didn't mean...
The hell you didn't.
And don't apologize
Look. boy. never quit. never lie
and never apologize.
Them's three things a man
ought to live by.
Luke. I know what you're feeling.
I know what that gal meant to you.
There's one thing I've learned in
this world. boy...
...and that is that grieving
don't help nobody.
Not the living or the dead.
I learned that the hard way.
Now. you're cut deep. boy.
But you ain't the first man that ever
felt that pain. you won't be the last.
You had a woman?
Had a wife.
And you loved her?
More than this whole world.
She was the fiercest. freest.
proudest damn woman any man ever knew.
She was a full-blooded Cherokee.
Had a mouth like wild strawberries
and honey.
She moved to a man
like a mountain cat...
...smooth. swift. strong.
Near drowned in the taste
and feel of her.
When she give me a son...
...I figured there wasn't a man
on this earth...
...had anything near as good
as I did.
You had a son?
Happiest little feller ever formed
from the pain of a woman.
He swam in sunshine.
that's what she used to say.
She was right.
Well. what happened to him?
We were headed up into
the Big Horn countries...
...late in the fall. do some trapping.
Little feller. he... He wasn't more
than a couple year old.
He sure loved being out
in the trail. though.
Well. we come to an old
trapper's cabin.
I figured it'd be a pretty good place
for him and his ma to hole up...
...while I went out. set the traps and...
Well. I guess I was the best
part of a day's ride out when...
...when the blizzard hit.
Must've dropped 40. 50 degrees
in a couple of hour.
Well. they run out of firewood
in the cabin.
She could've took
the cold all right. but...
...she was worried about the boy.
So she went outside...
...see if she could find
something to burn.
That little feller. he...
...somehow he pulled
the coal oil lamp down...
...set the blanket afire.
Didn't take more than a...
More than a few seconds to turn
that cabin into a blazing hell.
She come back in. tried to save him. but...
...it was too late.
By the time I got back. why...
...she was setting out in the snow...
...holding what was left
of our little boy in her arms...
...singing her death song.
She just lived long enough to...
...tell me what happened.
My God.
Luke. you know...
...if we could see down the road
in the beginning...
...what was waiting for us...
...reckon lot of us wouldn't go on.
Just the same.
we owe a debt. boy. all of us.
Just for the gift of living...
...for the shining times
we got to taste along the way.
Luke. what you gotta do is stop
looking back on that that hurt you.
You gotta start giving thanks...
...that the sun's still shining
and the world's still kicking.
That you're still part of it.
Now. I'll tell you something else.
boy...
...no man ever looked old Satan
in the eye...
...or walked through
the valley of despair...
...that didn't come out a better man
for having been through it.
Yes. sir.
Luke...
...you're the only living soul
I've ever told this story to.
Kind of like to keep it that way.
you hear me?
I hear you.
This is quite a posse
you put together. sheriff.
Ever since the sun went down
they've been jumping at every sound.
What's the matter?
They afraid of the dark?
No. they ain't.
It's Zeb Macahan.
He's a man.
Nothing more. nothing less.
Not according to them.
He's the best there is
when it comes to using a rifle...
...and when put to it. he can be mean
as fresh broke hell.
And besides. he ain't no outlaw!
But Luke Macahan is.
And now his uncle's riding with him.
that makes him an accomplice.
Maybe so.
But that ain't gonna mean nothing
to those men come sunup...
...when they're told
to rush them rocks.
Well...
Tell your men
they can ride out at dawn.
Do what?
But I want you to keep them
pinned down till then.
I don't understand.
I think I know where they're headed.
I ride out now.
I can be there before them.
Oh. that is good thinking.
Mr. Grey! Real good!
I thought you'd like it.
Make sure they know you're here.
Keep a fire going...
...have your men
fire a shot up there now and then.
Sure. You bet.
Dawn. sheriff.
Don't pull out a minute before.
I want them to see you go.
Dawn!
What are they fixing to do?
They're pulling out.
I don't get it.
They're giving up a mite easy.
Yeah.
We best get out of here
before they change their mind.
Don't be foolish. girl.
Luke isn't here!
He's coming.
You stay away from us!
And just leave us alone!
Put that down.
- I'll stick you.
- No. you won't.
Yes. I will! I'll stick you!
You don't want to do that. huh?
All right. Ace. grab her.
You make a sound.
I'll break your arm.
I'll take these in now.
Mother!
Name's Grey.
in case you've forgotten. ma'am.
You can call me Martin.
if you like.
We're gonna spend
some time together.
Let her go!
Tell the boy to drop the gun.
ma'am...
...unless you're willing
to lose your daughter.
Josh. do as he says.
Josh!
What do you want?
Ah. there's no need
to get riled up. ma'am.
I'm what you might call...
...a bearer of good tidings.
Your son's coming home.
Maybe today. He's riding
with his uncle. Zeb Macahan.
Have a real family gathering.
Are you the law.
or a bounty hunter?
Well. you might say
I was the law.
And now I...
...I kind of work on my own.
Bounty hunter. Ma.
Anyway you put it.
Well.
How do you like the taste
of your own blood. boy?
There's only four of you. huh?
I don't know how long I'm gonna be here.
a day. maybe more. maybe less.
But there's gonna be some rules.
My rules.
No one's following.
I sure never seen a posse
like that one before.
Tree their man.
then ride off and leave him.
Well. it could be
that sheriff's doing.
I mean it was getting close
to breakfast.
Say. speaking of eating...
...won't be long and we'll be tasting
your ma's cooking.
Yeah.
Uncle Zeb?
Thanks for telling me about
your wife and son.
I know how hard it was for you.
But it helped.
I'm just sorry
you got tied up in all this.
You know. you could be wanted too.
Hell. it wouldn't be the first time
I was ever a-straddle of the law...
...or in jail neither.
You been locked up?
Heh. time or two.
Once down in Mexico. why.
me and my partner. Bo Weed...
...we busted out down there. Ha!
Whole thing started over a little
dark-haired señorita that we was both...
I best save that story for later.
Your ma would think it was a bad influence.
Heh. Come on.
Sit down. girls. breakfast is ready.
Smells pretty good. doesn't it?
You're not welcome to join us.
Mr. Grey.
Well. then I'll serve myself.
Your rules. Mr. Grey.
Dear Lord. we humbly thank thee
for thy many blessings...
...and for this food
thou has put before us. amen.
Amen.
Josh?
Yes. Ma?
You better feed the cow
and close the barn door.
Wait a minute.
What is it?
I don't want nobody
out of my sight.
You put all our guns
down the well. remember?
Let the little girl do it.
Jessie...
In the loft there's a gun
in your father's trunk.
I want you to get it
and put it on the shelf by the barn door.
What you talking about?
I was just telling her how much oats
to feed the cow.
We are a family. Mr. Grey...
...we have a right to talk.
Half a bucket. Jessie.
Do you intend to take my son
in alive. Mr. Grey?
It's up to him.
What about Zeb?
What are you gonna do about him?
Wait till the time comes.
Bushwacking?
That part of your rules too.
Mr. Grey?
Whatever gets the job done. ma'am.
Why so long?
Not only the cow. the horses too.
My horse?
You can feed him yourself.
Get in the house.
I said get in the house!
You expected them by now. didn't you?
How do you know
they're coming here?
I know.
How?
Hunted enough men to know.
No place to run...
...they head for home.
Family. warmth.
A safe place.
Where you going?
It's private.
All right. Go straight there
and straight back.
Are you gonna kill my brother?
I never set out to kill a man. missy.
Only when I have a reason.
Bounty money?
Money's got nothing
to do with your brother.
Thought you was going to
the privy?
Boy!
Get out there and chop some wood.
I already chopped some wood.
Then chop some more.
Why?
Because it's too quiet out there.
Zeb Macahan's got instincts
like an animal.
He senses something different
he won't come in. Now get out there!
What do you do this time of day?
Huh?
I tend the wash. or the vegetables.
And the girls?
Baking.
I'm out in the fields working.
Not today. you're not.
Today you're gonna be
chopping wood so I can see you.
If I were you. I'd get out there.
Tend to the wash!
Mrs. Macahan.
They show up and you warn them...
...you'll regret it
the rest of your life.
And you. I want you to keep the fire going.
smoke coming out of that chimney.
Your sister comes back. stay with her.
Keep smoke coming out of that chimney.
The gun?
Jessie said she dropped it
near the barn door.
Gotta make a move now. Josh.
I'll go for the gun.
If you can just get him away
from the window long enough.
We can handle it. Ma.
We've got to.
When you hear a ruckus.
you go get the gun.
- Just make sure he's away from the window.
- I will.
Now. what you doing?
I'm helping the girls.
Well. how's it coming?
Oh. fine. Ma.
we're just baking some bread.
Luke's favorite kind.
I want you girls to stay away
from the stove.
All right. where's the water?
Under there.
Some more water. get more water!
You take care of that one.
You're coming from the barn.
- I heard some noises...
- Bring your hand from behind your back.
You heard me! Bring it out!
Josh!
Come pretty close. didn't you?
You're lucky
you're not both dead.
Next time you will be.
Oh. Josh!
There she is.
Sure looks good.
All right.
They're here.
Any of you makes a sound.
I'll kill you.
Looks pretty quiet.
I wonder where everybody is.
It's about lunchtime.
they're probably eating.
I hope there's something left. I'm starved.
I know what you mean.
I've been thinking about your ma's
biscuits for the last ten miles.
No!
You follow me out real close.
Well. Luke. we made it.
All right!
Hold it right there! Now...
Just clear the pistols from their holster.
drop them on the ground real slow.
I should have killed you
when I had the chance. mister.
If it had been me. I would have.
Grey. it's me you want. I'll go with
you peaceable. but leave them alone.
Take a good look at him.
Mrs. Macahan...
...he'll be saying goodbye
in a minute.
Can't we have a little time?
No. Boy!
Get my horse out of the barn.
The other way!
Now!
You're not gonna get out of this.
Grey.
I'm gonna get a hand on you...
...and it's gonna be all over.
Aah!
Luke!
Kate? Ready when you are.
A lot happened here.
Some of it good. some bad.
It's all behind us now.
We're ready to go on. Zeb...
...on to Oregon.
Let's do her.
Careful. Careful.
All right. Ma. Ah!
Oh. thanks. Ma.
I'll help you with that.
Thought you were the one
against carrying a heavy load.
Well. that glass is hard
to come by. Luke.
Least ways out here it is.
Uncle Zeb?
- Got it?
- Yeah. I got it.
Easy now. boys. easy.
There we go.
Well. we're all ready to go.
Uncle Zeb.
Looks like it.
Yes. sir.
Looks so empty.
Can we just go. please?
Think Laura's got the right idea.
- Let's get started.
- All right.
Come on. Sam.
Scoot! Giddyap!
How far is it. Uncle Zeb?
It's a long way. honey...
...and we're gonna feel
every mile of it.
Zeb. thanks for bringing Luke back.
Heh. heh. That's all right. Kate.
I figured that'd be the only way
we'd ever get you off that land.
Forgive me for saying some
of those things I said to you.
Ha. Forget it.
Some of them was true.
Uncle Zeb. hold up.
Uncle Zeb.
can I ask you a question?
Well. as long as
it ain't too personal.
We're starting awfully late in the year.
We gonna make it to Oregon?
Yeah. I was afraid somebody
was gonna ask me that.
Long as you did. the answer's no.
Then why we leaving here?
You still got a price
on your head in Missouri. boy.
The farther we get you away
from there...
...the safer you're gonna be.
We won't get to Oregon
this year. huh?
No. but we'll get through the Rockies
and that's the main thing.
Some mighty pretty country west
of the divide we can winter in.
It's hard to believe.
We started out for Oregon four years ago
and we're still only halfway there.
Yeah. cheer up. Luke.
It ain't going anywhere.
it's waiting for us.
Hell. boy. you play
your cards right...
...your son might be the first
Macahan born in Oregon territory.
You think on that.
1865...
...two years from the time when
mighty herds of cattle...
...would move up the dusty trails
from Texas...
...four years from the time
when railroads...
...would tie two great
oceans together.
A time of turmoil.
of the gunfighter...
...and hell-for-leather cowboys.
And a time when the blood
of Indian and white man...
...stained a hundred battlefields.
But it was also a time of
opportunity for those who...
...like the Macahans...
...had the courage
to look to the West...
...in search of a new beginning.
Original Rip By mstoll
Resync/Corrections By Chuck
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org